so let's now revisit the topic of cache
misses when we have coherence going on
we have seen that caches have three C's
3 types of misses compulsory misses
conflict misses and capacity misses
remember that compulsory misses we have
them because we're accessing the block
for the first time so because it was
never in the cache we have to have this
miss capacity misses we have because the
block doesn't fit in a cache of this
size and conflict misses we have because
the cache doesn't have enough
associativity with coherence another see
we can now have a cache miss caused by
coherence for example when we read
something somebody writes it and we want
to read it again that would not be a
Miss except for coherence so we call
this type of a miss coherence miss so
remember that there is actually forces
the three we have seen before and
coherence miss there are really two
types of coherence misses what we have
seen so far is the true sharing type of
miss which occurs when different cores
access the same data so naturally we
have to perform coherence and thus have
some misses so for example if we read a
and then write a and then read a again
there are some misses necessary in order
to get the right behavior for the reads
but these were all happening on the same
data there is another type of coherence
miss called false sharing which occurs
when different cores access different
data so there shouldn't be any coherence
messages because of that except that
these data items are in the same block
so it's called false sharing because
really there is no true data sharing but
as far as coherence is concerned we do
everything at the ground of cache blocks
so two items being in the same block
makes them behave like the same item as
far as coherence is concerned